（莎士比亚戏剧《麦克白》，麦克白刺杀国王一幕）
有趣，大角星人演的麦克白
Interesting, an Arcturian Macbeth.
注意他
Watch him.
注意麦克白
Watch Macbeth.
他死了吗？
Is he dead?
说话呀
Speak.
登肯国王死了吗？
Is King Duncan dead?
大洋里所有的水
Will all great Neptune's ocean wash this blood
能够洗净我手上的血迹吗？
clean from my hands?
他的声音
That voice.
好好回想
Think back.
舞台上的那个男人
That man on the stage.
我很确定
I'm certain of it.
他就是刽子手寇多斯
That's Kodos the Executioner.
它们要挖出我的眼睛！
They pluck out mine eyes!
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是进取号星舰的旅程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
五年目标：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新的生活与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢前往人迹罕至之地
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：薇拉 madscientist
校对：Micezhang xjCGI
第一季第13集
国王的良知
舰长日志，星历2817.6年
Captain's log, stardate 2817.6.
进取号星舰偏离预定航线
Starship Enterprise diverted from scheduled course.
目的：证实托马斯·雷顿博士发现的…
Purpose: to confirm discovery by Dr. Thomas Leighton
惊人的新合成食品
of an extraordinary new synthetic food
这种食品将会终结…
which would totally end the threat of famine
地球附近的塞尼亚·米诺殖民星的饥荒威胁
on Cygnia Minor, a nearby Earth colony.
你想让我浪费三光年的航行时间
Do you mean to tell me you've called me three light years off my course
就为了指控一个像寇多斯的演员吗？
just to accuse an actor of being Kodos?
他就是寇多斯，我很肯定
He is Kodos. I am sure of it.
你说你发现了一种新的压缩食物
You said you discovered a new food concentrate.
日志该如何记录，写你撒谎吗？
What am I supposed to put in my log, that you lied?
用错误信息改变星舰航向吗？
That you diverted a starship with false information?
你捅了篓子，还连累到我
You're not only in trouble, you've put me in trouble too.
我是为了抓捕寇多斯
I did it to trap Kodos.
寇多斯…
Kodos...
…已经死了
...is dead.
是吗？大家都认同吗？
Is he? Is anyone sure?
就凭具烧得面目全非的尸体吗？
A body burned beyond recognition?
汤姆，当局多年前就结束了调查
Tom, the authorities closed the book on that case years ago.
那我们重新调查
Then let's reopen it.
吉姆，他杀了4000人
Jim, 4000 people were butchered.
- 玛莎，你劝劝他好吗？ - 我劝不了，吉姆
- Martha, will you tell him? - I can't tell him anything, Jim.
自从演出团来了之后他就这样了
He's been like this since the company of actors arrived.
寇多斯死了，我很满意
Kodos is dead. I'm satisfied with that.
我可不满意
Well, I'm not.
我记得他
I remember him.
他的声音
That voice.
他的恶行
The bloody thing he did.
吉姆，吉姆，你得帮帮我
Jim. Jim, I need your help.
我们中只有九、十个人见过寇多斯
There were only eight or nine of us who actually saw Kodos.
我算一个，你也算一个
I was one, you're another.
- 如果要指认他… - 他死了
- If he's to be exposed-- - He's dead.
那今晚我和玛莎在家招待的就是鬼了
Then it'll be a ghost Martha and I receive in our home tonight.
我邀请了整个演出团的人参加鸡尾酒会
I invited the entire company to a cocktail party.
我必须弄清楚
I have to be sure.
我得回星舰了
And I have to get back to my ship
还得要想想日志该怎么写
and figure out how I’m gonna enter all this in my log.
失陪了两位
Tom. Martha.
电脑图书馆
Library computer.
历史文件
History files.
主题：塔尔苏斯四号星的前总督寇多斯
Subject: former Governor Kodos of Tarsus IV,
人称刽子手寇多斯
also known as Kodos the Executioner.
之后再查演员安东·卡里迪安的背景资料
After that, background on actor Anton Karidian.
查找中
Working.
刽子手寇多斯，概要：
Kodos the Executioner. Summary:
塔尔苏斯四号星的总督，20年前
Governor of Tarsus IV, 20 Earth years ago.
实行军事管制
Invoked martial law,
屠杀了该星上来自地球的殖民人口的一半
slaughtered 50 percent of population Earth colony that planet.
地球军队赶到时发现他被烧焦的尸体
Burned body found when Earth forces arrived.
身份无法辨识
No positive identification.
调查结束
Case closed.
详细信息如下
Detailed information follows.
星历2794.7年
On stardate 2794.7,
- 寇多斯 - 停下
- Kodos-- - Stop.
安东·卡里迪安的资料
Information on Anton Karidian.
巡回演出团的主管和演员
Director and star of travelling company of actors
由银河文化交流项目赞助
sponsored by Galactic Cultural Exchange Project.
九年来进行官方巡回演出
Touring official installations last nine years.
女儿叫蕾诺尔，19岁，与其父亲巡回
Has daughter, Lenore, 19 years old. Travelling with--
停下，将演员卡里迪安和总督寇多斯
Stop. Give comparative identification between actor Karidian
进行身份对比
and Governor Kodos.
没有安东·卡里迪安的身份记录
No identification records available on actor Anton Karidian.
查找寇多斯死前演员卡里迪安的资料
Give information on Actor Karidian prior to Kodos' death.
20年之内
No information available Anton Karidian
没有安东·卡里迪安的资料
prior to 20 years ago.
寇多斯的照片
Photograph, Kodos.
卡里迪安的照片
Photograph, Karidian.
两张照片对比
Now photograph, both.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
你认识雷顿博士，对吧？
You know Dr. Leighton, don't you?
你怎么看待他的判断？
Would you say he's given to fantasy?
他是一位经验丰富的科学家
A good empirical research scientist.
稳重，名声好，有时会有伟大的发现
Steady, reputable, occasionally brilliant.
记忆力也特别好
With a very long memory.
这个我不太清楚，舰长
I have no information on that, captain.
我们已经准备好驶离轨道了
We are ready to leave orbit.
这次不忙着离开
We'll delay departure for a time.
我要重回那个星球
I'm beaming back down to the planet again.
- 汤姆在哪？ - 他去城里了
- Where's Tom? - He went to town.
他来电说他正在回来的路上
He called. He's on his way back.
大家都在露台上吧
The others are on the patio.
我就当你是迎宾了
I take it you're the welcoming committee.
这是给我的吗？
Is that for me?
当然
Why not?
我看了你们今晚的表演
I saw your performance tonight.
请允许我表达对你们的仰慕之情
May I extend my appreciation?
我父亲会很开心的，你是…？
My father will be delighted, Mr...? Mr...?
詹姆士·寇克，进取号舰长
Captain James Kirk, starship Enterprise.
我们很荣幸
We're honoured.
我原希望今晚能和令尊单独见面的
I had hoped to meet your father here tonight personally.
抱歉，寇克上校，他不喜欢见客
I'm sorry, Captain Kirk, he has a rigid rule about that.
他从没和别人单独见过面，他也不参加派对
He never sees anyone personally, and he never attends parties.
演员拒绝他的仰慕者啊？不常见啊
An actor turning away his admirers? Very unusual.
卡里迪安是个很不寻常的人
Karidian is a most unusual man.
你见过“麦克白”了吧
You saw Macbeth.
那就是我的父亲
That was my father.
好吧，我就跟“麦克白夫人”谈谈好了
Well, then I’ll talk to Lady Macbeth.
进取号舰长，有趣
So captain of the Enterprise, interesting.
麦克白夫人，也很有趣
So Lady Macbeth, interesting.
你们下一步什么打算？
What's your next move?
我们要在贝妮莎演两场剧
We play two performances at Benecia,
“女王星号”会带我们去
if the Astral queen can get us there.
是艘很好的星舰
She's a good ship.
谢谢
Thank you.
你演的麦克白夫人让人印象很深刻
You were very impressive as Lady Macbeth.
谢谢
Thank you.
我自己本人呢？
And as Lenore Karidian?
同样让人印象深刻
Very impressive.
蕾诺尔…
Lenore...
- …我想能再见到你 - 你是指演出吗？
- ...I'd like to see you again. - You mean professionally?
未必
Not necessarily.
我也想能和你再见面
I think I'd like that.
不过，我们有行程要赶
Unfortunately, we must keep a schedule.
你现在没行程，对吧？
You don't have a schedule now, do you?
你想我们离开这儿吗？
You mean leave?
- 但是我才刚到 - 我也是啊
- But I’ve only just arrived. - So have I.
- 你不喜欢在欢迎会上逗留太久 - 没错
- And you hate to overstay a welcome. - Exactly.
- 那好吧 - 好
- Why not? - Good.
我跟女主人说一声
I'll make our apologies to our hostess.
我们门外见
I'll meet you outside.
走累了吗？
Tired of walking?
没有，只是在想事情
No. Just thinking.
想什么？
About what?
在派对上，你是那么强势
At the party, you were such a brash young man.
- 现在呢？ - 有点不一样
- And now? - Now somehow different.
不是星舰的舰长，不是那个
Not a ship's captain, with all those people
在所有人面前强势自信的男人
to be strong and confident in front of.
你真的很可爱，不是吗？
No, you're really very dear, aren't you?
在某种程度上…
In some ways...
…非常孤独
...very lonely.
是汤姆·雷顿
It's Tom Leighton.
他死了
He's dead.
至少他现在安息了
At least he has peace now.
以前他从没安宁过
He never really had that before.
哦，要是汤姆的怀疑不属实
Oh, why was Tom killed
- 他怎么会被杀？ - 我不知道
- if what he suspected wasn't true? - I don't know.
我会尽力找出真相的
I'll try and find out.
哦，吉姆
Oh, Jim,
我会多想念他啊
how I’ll miss him.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 舰桥收到，舰长
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Bridge here, captain.
帮我接通轨道站女王星号的舰长琼·戴利
Put me through to Captain Jon Daily of the Astral queen on orbit station.
请尽快，好吗？
And put it on scramble, will you?
戴利舰长在线上，先生
Captain Daily's on, sir.
琼，我是吉姆·寇克
Jon, Jim Kirk.
你好，吉姆
Hi, Jim.
你能帮我个忙吗？
Can you do me a favour?
我欠你多着呢，尽管说
I owe you a dozen, just ask.
- 不要接你的乘客 - 你想让这些演员滞留在这吗？
- Don't make your pickup here. - You mean strand all those actors?
我来接他们，出什么麻烦的话，责任我来背
I'll pick them up. And if there's any trouble, it'll be my responsibility.
好的，还有其他的事吗？
Will do. Anything else?
这件事请务必保密，请接受我的谢意，完毕
Just keep this between the two of us and accept my thanks. Over and out.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 舰桥收到，舰长
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Bridge here, captain.
传送室，准备传送
Transporter Room, ready to beam up.
准备恢复原航线，舰长
Ready to resume course, captain.
我觉得我们应该接客人了
I think we're due for a pickup.
什么样的？人员还是货物？
What kind? Personnel? Cargo?
舰长，有位卡里迪安小姐被传到舰上
Captain, a Miss Karidian has been transported aboard ship.
她要求见你
She requests permission to see you.
- 让她到舰桥上来 - 好的
- Tell her to come up to the bridge. - All right.
陪同卡里迪安小姐前往舰桥
Escort Miss Karidian to the bridge.
你怎么知道这位小姐要来？
How did you know this lady was coming aboard?
我是舰长
I'm the captain.
寇克舰长，没想到我们这么快就再见面了
Captain Kirk, I didn't think we'd be meeting again so soon.
要是我告诉你这是我安排的，你可能不会相信
Well, you probably wouldn't believe me if I told you I arranged it.
不会，你这样说让我很开心
No, but it's a delightful thought.
舰长，恐怕我们需要你的帮助
Captain, I'm afraid we need your help.
我们被滞留了
We've been stranded.
貌似我们的交通工具拒绝我们搭乘
It seems that our transportation has cancelled out on us.
- 不能另外安排吗？ - 有，不过时间来不及
- Can't you make other arrangements? - Well, yes, but not in time.
我们的计划就像一串链条
You see, our schedule is like a chain
一环出错，整串链条就会断裂
One break, and it all collapses.
如果那样就太遗憾了
Be a shame if that happened.
要是有个好心人帮我们就好了
If ever we needed a Good Samaritan.
这样啊…
Well...
我请求你
I appeal to you.
我们的章程对搭载乘客有明确规定
The regulations are very clear about taking on passengers.
我和你做个交易，舰长
I'll make a bargain with you, captain.
- 你要拿什么做交易？ - 为全体舰员专场表演
- What have you got to trade? - A special performance for the crew,
换一次顺风船
in exchange for a lift.
你的提议很有趣
You make it sound very interesting.
我们的舰员巡航好久了
The crew has been on patrol for a long time.
他们可以在单调中歇口气
They could use a break in the monotony.
那你是答应了？
Then you'll do it?
你让我无法拒绝啊
You've got me backed into a corner.
要是他们看不到你们的演出，是不会放过我的
The men would never forgive me if I deprived them of your performance
当然还有你
and your presence.
谢谢，舰长，我万分感激
Thank you, captain. I'm eternally grateful.
我让演出团准备一下
I'll get the company ready.
这对他们太重要了
This means so much to them.
史波克，卡里迪安的演出团一登舰
Mr. Spock, prepare to leave orbit
就准备驶离轨道
as soon as the Karidian Company is aboard the ship.
我能问问我们的目的地吗，舰长？
May I enquire as to our course, captain?
贝妮莎殖民地
Benecia Colony.
贝妮莎殖民地离我们的目的地有八光年那么远
Benecia Colony is eight light years off our course.
如果我脑子不灵光了，会马上告诉你的
If my memory needs refreshing, I'll ask you for it.
在那之前，执行我的命令
In the meantime, follow my orders.
舰长日志，星历2818.9
Captain's log, stardate 2818.9.
我有很多疑问
There are many questions in my mind,
很多的可能，来自演员卡里迪安和他的女儿
too many perhaps, about the actor Karidian and his daughter.
个人来说，我几乎害怕知道答案
For personal reasons, I am almost afraid to learn the answers.
史波克
Mr. Spock,
预计到达时间，贝妮莎殖民地
ETA, the Benecia colony.
我们会在星历2825.3到达，舰长
We'll arrive stardate 2825.3, captain.
大概在当地时间15:00
Approximately 15:00 Benecia time.
电脑图书馆
Library computer.
问题数据提交到人事档案
Data on question submitted to personnel files.
数据被接受
Data being received.
寇多斯档案
Kodos file.
所有幸存者中，有九名目击者
Of all survivors, there are nine actual eyewitnesses
可以认证寇多斯
who can identify Kodos.
停下，列出名单
Stop. Give list.
寇克·J，现进取号舰长
Kirk, J., presently Enterprise captain,
雷顿·T，莫尔森·E
Leighton, T., Molson, E.,
莱利·K，伊姆斯·D
Riley, K., Eames, D.
停下
Stop.
那是星际服务部的上尉凯文·莱利吗？
Is that Star Service Lieutenant Kevin Riley?
确认
Affirmative.
莱利·凯文，现任职
Riley, Kevin, presently assigned
联邦星舰进取号通讯部
USS Enterprise Communications section.
停下
Stop.
- 史波克 - 舰长
- Mr. Spock. - Captain.
通讯部上尉凯文·莱利
Lieutenant Kevin Riley in Communications,
把他抽调到轮机甲板层
I wish to have him transferred down to the engineering decks.
他就是从轮机甲板层调任上来的
He came up from Engineering, captain.
- 把他送回去吧 - 有什么解释吗？
- Well, I’m sending him back. - Any explanation?
他是一名优秀的年轻官员
He's a fine young officer.
他肯定认为这是纪律处分
He's bound to consider this transfer a disciplinary action.
我不想谈论这件事，史波克，请执行我的命令
I don't wish to discuss it, Mr. Spock. Please follow my orders.
史波克，高层领导往往踽踽独行
Mr. Spock, the man on top walks a lonely street.
命令的链锁是个锁套
The chain of command is often a noose.
别跟我说你的哲学隐喻了，医生
Spare me your philosophical metaphors, doctor.
舰长的行为很古怪
The captain is acting strangely.
我想问你有没有注意到
I'm asking if you've noticed.
没有，你知不知道这周我头一次
Negative. Do you know this is the first time in a week
有时间喝喝酒？
that I've had time for a drop of the true?
要不要来一杯，史波克？
Would you care for a drink, Mr. Spock?
我的父辈差点在酒精的诱惑下亡族灭种
My father's race was spared the dubious benefits of alcohol.
哦，现在我知道他们为什么被征服了
Oh, now I know why they were conquered.
你干嘛那么忧心忡忡？
What are you so worried about, anyway?
吉姆做什么自己心里有数
I find Jim generally knows what he's doing.
载乘那些演员不合他的逻辑
It was illogical for him to bring those players aboard.
不合逻辑？
Illogical?
你看到那个小美人朱丽叶了吗？
Did you get a look at that little Juliet?
那真是一个让人怦然心动的尤物
That's a pretty exciting creature.
当然，你的个人特质让你屏蔽掉了这点
Of course, your personal chemistry would prevent you from seeing that.
你有没有想过他也许仅仅是喜欢姑娘而已？
Did it ever occur to you that he simply might like the girl?
想过
It occurred.
- 我排除了这一点 - 你当然会
- I dismissed it. - You would.
你知道他把上尉莱利调到轮机甲板层了吗？
Did you know that he transferred Lieutenant Riley to Engineering?
这儿发生的很多事我都不知道
There are lots of things that go on around here
史波克
that I don't know, Mr. Spock.
他是舰长，他想怎么调就怎么调
He's the captain, he can transfer people as he pleases.
你可以把这看做是一百卷
You can look that up in a hundred volumes
宇宙规则的其中一种，好吗？
of space regulations somewhere, all right?
好啦，来吧，喝一杯
All right. Now come on, have a drink.
不了，谢谢
No, thank you.
不客气，那我可喝了
Well, you're welcome, but I will.
史波克，要是你不跟我一块喝
And please, Mr. Spock, if you won't join me,
请别阻碍我喝酒
don't disapprove of me.
至少在你没尝过之前别这么做，好吗？
At least not until you've tried it, huh?
这里是观测甲板
This is the observation deck.
那是穿梭机所在的飞行甲板
That's the flight deck down there with a shuttlecraft.
- 有趣 - 对啊
- Interesting. - Isn't it?
- 告诉我，寇克舰长 - 随便问
- Tell me, Captain Kirk. - Anything.
你是不是为此专门点了柔光模式？
Did you order the soft lights especially for the occasion?
要是我点了柔光模式
If I had ordered soft lights,
我就顺便会安排音乐和鲜花
I'd also have arranged for music and flowers.
不幸的是，没这回事，在进取号上
Unfortunately, it isn't so. On the Enterprise,
我们尽可能调成地球上白天黑夜的模式
we try to duplicate Earth conditions of night and day as closely as possible.
星光皎皎，明亮闪耀
Star light, star bright
我心淼淼，太空逍遥
I wish I may, I wish I might
- 你还记得吗，舰长？ - 流传很久了
- Do you remember that, captain? - It's very old.
几乎和这些星球一样古老
Almost as old as the stars themselves.
还有这艘星舰
And this ship.
所有的力量，穿梭航行，颠簸震动
All this power, surging and throbbing,
还是会平稳前行
yet under control.
你喜欢这样吗，舰长？
Are you like that, captain?
这些力量全都在你的指挥之下
All this power at your command.
尽管你做出的这些决定
Yet the decisions that you have to make--
来自于一个地球人
Come from a very human source.
你是吗？地球人？
Are you, captain? Human?
这点不用怀疑
You can count on it.
跟我说说你们星球上的女人，舰长
Tell me about the women in your world, captain.
我更想知道关于你的事情
I'd rather talk about you.
你肯定非常想表演
You must have wanted to perform
从你第一次看到父亲的演出起
since the first time you saw your father act.
- 什么时候？ - 最开始的时候
- When was that? - In the beginning.
- 来说说看 - 这不公平
- Tell me about it. - That's not fair.
你还没回答我关于女人的问题
You haven't answered my question about the women.
你想知道些什么？
What would you like to know?
她们是否已经被机器改造了
Has the machine changed them,
使得她们只是单纯的人类，而不是女人
made them just people instead of women?
世界或许在变化，星系或许会解体
Worlds may change, galaxies disintegrate,
然而女人，一直是女人
but a woman always remains a woman.
所有的这一切
All this...
包括权利在内
...and power too.
所有星球的“凯撒”
Caesar of the stars.
克里欧佩特拉（埃及艳后）也要崇拜他
And Cleopatra to worship him.
电脑图书馆
Library computer.
我需要下列所有人的完整档案
Full personal dossiers on the following names.
托马斯·雷顿博士
Dr. Thomas Leighton.
安东·卡里迪安
Anton Karidian.
凯文·莱利上尉
Lieutenant Kevin Riley.
和詹姆士·T·寇克舰长
And Captain James T. Kirk.
已完成，待命中
Accomplished. Standing by.
核对他们的档案，查找关联项
Correlate. Check their past histories.
报告所有在他们档案中共同出现的部分
Report any item, any past episode or experience they all have in common.
确认
Affirmative.
我很高兴你能为我们…
I appreciate whatever concern you may have
- 星舰的和谐着想，史波克先生 - 我还是继续说吧，医生
- for the ship's company, Mr. Spock-- - I will continue, doctor.
根据我们电脑图书馆的记录
According to our library banks,
始于塔尔苏斯4号对地球的殖民
it started on the Earth colony of Tarsus IV
那时大部分食物被一种外来的真菌污染
when the food supply was attacked by an exotic fungus and largely destroyed.
8000名殖民者实际上已经没有食物了
There were over 8000 colonists and virtually no food.
就在那时，总督寇多斯获得独裁的权力
And that was when Governor Kodos seized full power
- 并发布了紧急戒严令 - 我听说了
- and declared emergency martial law. - I've heard of it.
你也许还不清楚事情的全部
You may not have heard it all
寇多斯开始将所有的殖民者划分成两部分
Kodos began to separate the colonists.
一部分人将获得定期的粮食补给得以存活
Some would live, be rationed whatever food was left.
而剩下的那部分殖民者将面临死亡
The remainder would be immediately put to death.
显然，这是他自己的择优理论
Apparently, he had his own theories of eugenics.
- 不幸地，他不是第一个这样做的人 - 或许不是
- Unfortunately, he wasn't the first. - Perhaps not.
但这无疑是相当残忍的
But he was certainly among the most ruthless.
随意决定谁生谁死
To decide arbitrarily who would survive and who would not,
就凭他个人的标准
using his own personal standards,
无情的执行这一决策
and then to implement his decision without mercy.
父母就在孩子们的眼前死去，整个家庭就此瓦解
Children watching their parents die, whole families destroyed.
4000多人
Over 4000 people.
一下子全死了，不再有任何痛苦，但他们已经死了
They died quickly, without pain, but they died.
等救援到时已经晚了，已经无法挽回了
Relief arrived, but too late to prevent the executions.
而寇多斯，活不见人，死不见尸
And Kodos, there never was a positive identification of his body.
但这和卡里迪安有什么关系
But what has Karidian to do with it?
卡里迪安的出现，几乎就从寇多斯失踪那天开始
His history begins almost to the day where Kodos disappeared.
然后你认为吉姆怀疑他是寇多斯？
And you think Jim suspects he's Kodos?
希望如此
He'd better.
有九位目击者在那场大屠杀中幸存下来
There were nine eyewitnesses who survived the massacre,
他们都亲眼见过寇多斯
who had actually seen Kodos with their own eyes.
吉姆·寇克就是其中一人
Jim Kirk was one of them.
除了莱利和舰长寇克
With the exception of Riley and Captain Kirk,
其余的目击者都死了
every other eyewitness is dead.
然后电脑图书馆的记录显示，无论他们在哪儿
And my library computer shows that wherever they were,
地球，殖民地，还是飞船
on Earth, on a colony or aboard ship,
卡里迪安的演员们都离他们的死亡现场不远
the Karidian Company of Players was somewhere near when they died.
难以置信
It's unbelievable.
嘿，娱乐室的各位
Hey, Rec Room, somebody.
回句话
Talk to me.
我是拉里·马特森
Larry Matson here.
是你吗，莱利？什么事？
Is that you, Riley? What's up?
已经不是我了
Not me.
那个我已经死在轮机室了
I am down in the Engineering Room.
- 就是说你表现的不乖了？ - 也许吧
- So you've been a bad boy? - Maybe so.
无论我做了什么，他们还是什么都不对我说
Whatever I’ve done, they're sure keeping it a secret from me.
嘿，是乌乎拉在弹琴吗，让我和她说几句
Hey, is that Uhura playing? Let me talk to her.
我觉得他现在很受伤
I think his heart is sore.
我能为你做些什么呢，莱利？
What can I do for you, Riley?
弹一曲吧
A song.
来首情歌
Make it a love song.
能让我感到慰藉就好
Just something to reassure me
让我觉得自己不是这宇宙唯一的活物，恩？
I'm not the only living thing left in the universe, huh?
对，你不是，我将证明给你看
Well, you're not. I'll prove it to you.
阴沉又昏暗的天空
The skies are green and glowing
我的心在哪
where my heart is
香味从哪飘来
Where the scented
月亮花在绽放着
Lunar flower's growing
在远离星系
Somewhere
远离心大星的
Beyond the stars
某处
Beyond Antares
我会回来的
I'll be back
即使渡过无限的岁月
Though it takes forever
永远
Forever
仅仅一天
Is just a day
成了永远
Forever
不过是再次的旅行
Is just another journey
明天
Tomorrow
在路边小憩片刻
A stop along the way
让岁月就这样流走吧
Then let the years go fading
我的心在哪
where my heart is
我的爱在哪
where my love eternally
永远的等着我
Is waiting
在远离星系
Somewhere
远离心大星的
Beyond the stars
某处
Beyond Antares
你觉得如何，莱利？
How'd you like that, Riley?
快救救我
Help me, please.
你必须得治好他
You've got to pull him through.
我不一定能行
I'm not sure I can.
如果他死了
If he dies,
那么唯一能指证寇多斯的人就只有舰长了
the only one who'll be able to identify Kodos is the captain.
他将成为下一个目标
And he'll be the next target.
舰长，星历2819.1
Captain's log, stardate 2819.1.
船员莱利的状况正在恶化
Ship's Officer Riley's condition worsening.
麦考伊医生正在研究病因和研制解药
Dr. McCoy making lab analysis to determine cause and antidote.
大家都非常的担心
Entire crew deeply concerned.
至今，实验数据显示
As of this date, lab report indicates presence
他摄入了大量的四氢化萘铋溶胶
of appreciable amount of tetralubisol,
高挥发性的飞船专用的润滑剂
a highly volatile lubricant in use aboard ship.
有人想毒死他
Someone tried to poison him.
四氢化萘铋溶胶是种乳白色的物质
Tetralubisol is a milky substance.
一般人容易混淆，误放了进去
Someone could've gotten careless, made a mistake.
你我都不相信这点，我想让船长过目这份报告
I don't believe that, neither do you. I want the captain to see that report.
先等我完成记录
When I've finished logging it.
就现在
Now.
好吧
All right.
进来
Come.
- 关于上尉莱利的报告 - 他现在状况如何？
- My report on Lieutenant Riley. - Will he make it?
很大机会康复
He's got a good chance.
让我们就此预测你的命运如何，船长？
Can we predict the same for you, captain?
好吧，史波克先生，我们开始吧
All right, Mr. Spock, let's have it.
你和莱利上尉都是目击者
Lieutenant Riley was a witness. So were you.
- 好的 - 有人想杀害他
- All right. - Someone tried to kill him.
- 也可能是场意外 - 你应该明白
- Could've been an accident. - You should be told the difference
到底是固执己见还是相信经验，医生
between empiricism and stubbornness, doctor.
和你一样，我也通过电脑图书馆核查过了
I checked with the library computer just as you did.
我也得到了相同的信息
I got the same information.
你做的是不是有点过分了，史波克先生
Aren't you getting a little out of line, Mr. Spock?
- 这是我的私事 - 这也与我有关
- My personal business-- - Is my personal business
当此事威胁到飞船的正常运作的时候
when it might interfere with the smooth operation of this ship.
- 你觉得有这个可能？ - 有这可能
- You think that happened? - It could happen.
我不喜欢任何人插手我的私事
I don't like anyone meddling in my affairs,
- 只要我是舰长就不能 - 吉姆
- not even my second in command. - Jim,
- 史波克只是想… - 我知道他想干嘛
- Spock's simply trying-- - I know what he's trying to do.
这是他的工作，你也清楚
It's his job, and you know it.
你也知道，什么都还没有证据
Then you also know that nothing is proven.
即使是在宇宙的这个角落里，船长，2加2还是等于4
Even in this corner of the galaxy, captain, two plus two equals four.
很明显，有人想试图杀害你
Almost certainly, an attempt will be made to kill you.
你为何要引火烧身？
Why do you invite death?
不
I'm not.
我只相信正义
I'm interested in justice.
是吗？
Are you?
你确定这不是一场复仇？
Are you sure it's not vengeance?
我也不确定
No, I'm not sure.
我希望能确定
I wish I was.
我已经在做前所未有的尝试了
I've done things I've never done before.
我已经在以我的前途“赌博”了
I've placed my command in jeopardy.
但从现在起，我必须要确定卡里迪安是否就是寇多斯
From here on, I’ve got to determine whether or not Karidian is Kodos.
他就是
He is.
你好像非常肯定
You sound certain.
我希望能和你一样确定
I wish I could be.
至少在指控他之前，我必须要确定
Before I accuse a man of that, I've got to be.
20年前，我见过他一次
I saw him once, 20 years ago.
人会变，记忆也会变
Men change. Memory changes.
现在在我看来，他是位演员，他可以改变相貌
I look at him now, he's an actor. He could've changed his appearance.
不
No.
逻辑推断是不够的
Logic is not enough.
我必须用自己的方式
I've got to feel my way,
百分百的确定下来
make absolutely sure.
你确定了他就是寇多斯又怎样？然后怎么做？
What if you decide he is Kodos? What then?
你难道想扮演上帝，带着他的头颅向众人宣告你的胜利？
Do you play God, carry his head through the corridors in triumph?
逝去的生命已无法挽回了，吉姆
That won't bring back the dead, Jim.
不
No.
但他们会瞑目的
But they may rest easier.
事情是这样的，船长
Logic, captain.
雷顿博士被杀害时卡里迪安的剧团刚好在Q星球上
Dr. Leighton was murdered while the Karidian Company was on Planet Q.
现在，又有人想试图杀害莱利
Now an attempt has been made against Riley
刚好他们剧团就在我们船上
while the company is onboard.
医生还无法断定这就是一起谋杀案
Doc isn't sure there was a murder attempt.
并且，我已经有办法证明…
Besides, I have an idea that may prove--
听，你听到没？
Listen. Do you hear it?
- 低沉的嗡嗡声 - 是相位枪
- That low hum. - A phaser.
超负荷状态
On overload.
我是船长
This is the captain.
有台超负荷的相位枪在我房间里
There's a phaser on overload in my quarters.
一旦爆炸，将炸穿整个甲板
If it blows, it'll take out the entire deck.
所有在爆炸范围内的人员迅速撤离
Evacuate all personnel in this quadrant.
2级红色警戒
Double red alert.
- 你快出去 - 你也不能呆在这
- You get out of here. - You can't stay.
快，封锁这片区域，快走，我来找
Go on, block off this section. Hurry, I'll find it.
迅速离开这片区域，马上封锁
Evacuate this section. Seal it off.
清空C4和C5区域
Clear sections C4 and C5.
我们早该谈谈了，不是么？
We're overdue for our talk, aren't we?
希望你能够尊重我的隐私，船长
I had hoped you would've respected my privacy, captain.
就在刚才，我们差点就被卷入爆炸之中
A moment ago, we narrowly averted an explosion
那威力足以摧毁数个甲板
which would've destroyed several decks of this ship.
在那之前，又有人试图毒害我们的船员
Before that, someone tried to poison one of my crewmen.
- 我表示遗憾 - 你肯定会的
- I'm sorry to hear that. - I'm sure you are.
你是寇多斯吗？
Are you Kodos?
我在问你话
I asked you a question.
- 你相信我是吗？ - 我信
- Do you believe that I am? - I do.
如果你愿意相信，那么我就是寇多斯
Then I am Kodos, if it pleases you to believe so.
我是位演员，我有很多身份
I'm an actor. I play many parts.
你现在确实是位演员
You're an actor now.
但20年前呢？
What were you 20 years ago?
年轻些，船长
Younger, captain.
非常的年轻
Much younger.
我也是
So was I.
但我还记得
But I remember.
看看你是否还记得
Let's see if you do.
把这个对着墙上的对讲机朗读一遍
Read this into that communicator on the wall.
你的声音将被记录下来
It will be recorded,
拿去和寇多斯的声音文件对比
and compared to a piece of Kodos' voice film we have in our files.
这项检测精度很高
The test is virtually infallible.
它将告诉我们你到底是卡里迪安
It will tell us whether you're Karidian
还是刽子手寇多斯
or Kodos the Executioner.
准备就绪
Ready for voice test.
掩饰你的声音是毫无意义的
Disguising your voice will make no difference.
革命非常的成功
"The revolution is successful,
但人们的存活得依赖于严厉的措施
but survival depends on drastic measures.
你的存在将会对安定的社会构成威胁
Your continued existence represents a threat to the well-being of society.
你们的存活将会是
Your lives mean slow death
这殖民地上更有存活价值的殖民者的慢性毒药
to the more valued members of the colony.
因此，我别无选择，将你们判处死刑
Therefore, I have no alternative but to sentence you to death.
你们的死亡将不可避免
Your execution is so ordered.
寇多斯，塔尔苏斯4号的总督
Signed Kodos, Governor of Tarsus IV."
我还记得这些话，并已将它们记下
I remember the words. I wrote them down.
你似乎很了解这段文字
You said them like you knew them.
你就没看几眼稿子
You hardly glanced at the paper.
- 我有快速学习的能力 - 你确定？
- I learn my parts very quickly. - Are you sure?
你确定没有在一群被胁迫的人面前发表过此类演讲
You sure you didn't act this role out in front of a captive audience
在一群曾被你无情的夺去生命的人面前？
whom you blasted out of existence without mercy?
我感觉仁慈一词从你嘴里说出非常的不合适，船长
I find your use of the word "mercy" strangely inappropriate, captain.
站在这的你，是当今高科技社会标志性的体现
Here you stand, a perfect symbol of our technical society.
机械化，电子化
Mechanized, electronicized,
而不是一个完整的人
and not very human.
你早已失去了人性
You've done away with humanity.
通过利用自己的资源去努力实现伟大的理想
The striving of man to achieve greatness through his own resources.
人类早已开始使用工具
We've armed man with tools.
为了卓越的奋斗还在继续，而寇多斯…
The striving for greatness continues. But Kodos--
- 寇多斯，无论他过去是谁 - 还是现在是谁
- Kodos, whoever he was-- - Or is.
或者现在是谁
Or is.
寇多斯决定了他人的生死
Kodos made a decision of life and death.
一些人必须得死，而另一些人也许能够存活
Some had to die that others might live.
你也有着至高的决策权，船长，你应该能明白的
You're a man of decision, captain. You ought to understand that.
我所知道的只有4000人被无辜的屠杀
All I understand is that 4000 people were needlessly butchered.
为了拯救剩下的4000人
In order to save 4000 others.
如果当时的救援能再晚些到达
And if the supply ships hadn't come earlier than expected,
你所谓的寇多斯也许将名垂青史
this Kodos of yours might have gone down in history as a great hero.
事实并非如此，历史已作出判决
But he didn't, and history has made its judgement.
如果你确信我就是寇多斯
If you're so sure that I’m Kodos,
为什么不赶快杀了我？
why not kill me now?
让这血腥的复仇迎接最终的审判
Let bloody vengeance take its final course,
再来看看这样做又有何意义
and see what difference it makes to this universe of yours.
美丽的世界依然存在，并未改变
Those beautiful words, well acted, change nothing.
不，我不这么认为
No, I suppose not.
他们仅仅是工具，就像这艘飞船
They're merely tools, like this ship of yours.
20年前根本没有安东·卡里迪安的任何记录
There are no previous records to Anton Karidian prior to 20 years ago.
血肉
Blood thins,
已模糊
body fails,
一个人最终为着失去的记忆心怀感激
and one is finally grateful for a failing memory.
我已不再珍视生命，包括我自己的
I no longer treasure life, not even my own.
我累了
I am tired.
过去已成空白
And the past is a blank.
你想知道的都已经清楚了吗，寇克舰长？
Did you get everything you wanted, Captain Kirk?
如果我清楚了…
If I had gotten...
我想知道的一切…
...everything I wanted...
你就不会活着走出这个房间了
...you might not walk out of this room alive.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
你现在最好休息下
You better rest now.
在你光辉的外表下暴露出了残暴，舰长
There's a stain of cruelty on your shining armour, captain.
你原本可以放过我们俩
You could've spared him and me.
你刚说过使用工具
You talked of using tools.
在你眼里，我也是工具，不是吗？
I was a tool, wasn't I?
一个被利用去对付我父亲的工具
A tool to use against my father.
一开始，也许是这样
In the beginning, perhaps.
但晚些时候，我想让自己能做的更好
But later, I wanted it to be more than that.
晚些，一切都是晚那么一些
Later. Everything's always later.
晚些，最晚
Later, latest.
非常的晚了
Too late.
实在是太晚了，舰长
Too late, captain.
你就像这飞船
You are like your ship,
能力强大，但不能算作个人
powerful and not human.
在你的心里没有仁慈
There is no mercy in you.
如果他是寇多斯
If he is Kodos,
则我对他已经够仁慈了
then I’ve shown him more mercy than he deserves.
如果他不是
And if he isn't,
我就不会伤害你们，会让你们在贝妮莎下船
then we'll let you off at Benecia, and no harm done.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk,
你是什么人，能决定伤害是否已造成？
who are you to say what harm was done?
那我该是什么人？
Who do I have to be?
治疗记录
Medical log.
莱利上尉已顺利康复并不再受管制
Lieutenant Riley sufficiently recovered to be discharged,
但是舰长仅将他的活动范围限于医务室
but captain has ordered him restricted to Sickbay
防止他与自称是卡里迪安…
to prevent contact with passenger who calls himself Karidian
但被怀疑是刽子手寇多斯的乘客接触
and is suspected of being Kodos the Executioner
而寇多斯杀害了上尉的家人
and of murdering the lieutenant's family.
舰长日志，星历2819.8
Captain's log, stardate 2819.8.
嫌疑人已被监视
Suspect under surveillance.
关键区域已进入双重戒备
Strategic areas under double guard.
卡里迪安的演出照常进行
Performance of the Karidian Players taking place as scheduled.
今晚，卡里迪安居然将为大家带来话剧《哈姆雷特》
Tonight, the Karidian Players present Hamlet,
为大家演绎另一个星际中的故事
another in a series of living plays presented in space,
将以忠于传统古典戏剧的方式演出
dedicated to the tradition of classic theatre.
《哈姆雷特》是在残酷的社会中诞生的一部残酷话剧
Hamlet is a violent play about violent times,
那个时代，生命不值一文，欲望代表一切
when life was cheap and ambition was God.
我确信匹配的很完全了，舰长
I believe we have a match, captain.
还不完全，史波克先生
But not an exact match, Mr. Spock.
我们是在决定一个人的生死
We're dealing with a man's life.
不能把决定权交给机器
No machine can make that decision.
在漫长的医学史中，没有哪位医生
In the long history of medicine, no doctor has ever caught
能够及时地赶到现场
the first few minutes of a play.
莱利，别忘了…
Riley, don't forget that--
莱利？
Riley?
- 寇克舰长，我是麦考依 - 收到
- Captain Kirk, McCoy here. - Yes, sir.
莱利不见了 当时我正在记录有关卡里迪安和寇多斯的事项
Riley's gone. I was recording my log about Karidian and Kodos.
- 如果被他听到了… - 我已经了解了，医生
- If he overheard-- - You've made your point, doctor.
舰长，这里是H甲板的安全中心
Captain. Security, H Deck.
武器库的锁已被破坏
The weapons locker has been broken into.
遗失了一把相位枪
One phaser is missing.
我是舰长，警备人员请注意
This is the captain. Security two alert.
找到并控制住上尉莱利
Find and restrain Lieutenant Kevin Riley.
他带着武器并很有可能前往剧院
He's armed and possibly headed towards the ship's theatre.
“你要把我带去哪里？”
Wither wilt thou lead me?
“说，我哪里也不去”
Speak; I'll go no further.
“听好了”
Mark me.
“我听着”
I will.
“我的死期即将到来”
My hour is almost come,
“当我引燃那折磨我的烈火”
when I to sulf'rous and tormenting fires
“我已放弃我自己时”
must render up myself.
“快说，我在听”
Speak. I am bound to hear.
“你才会复仇”
So art thou to revenge,
“你才会聆听”
when thou shalt hear.
“我的灵魂依然是你的父亲”
I am thy father's spirit,
“只因某些原因而行走夜路，走向灭亡”
doomed for a certain term to walk the night...
莱利，快回医务室去
Riley, get back to the Sickbay.
他杀了我的父母
He murdered my father and my mother.
你也许认错了
You could be wrong.
不要因为认错人而毁了你一辈子
Don't throw away your life on a mistake.
我没认错
I'm not wrong.
“但正因我不能说出我那囚室的秘密”
But that I am forbid to tell the secrets of my prison house...
我听得出他的声音
I know that voice.
那张脸，我见过
That face, I know it. I saw it.
他杀了我父母
He murdered them.
“才折磨着你的心智”
--would harrow up thy soul,
“冻结了你的鲜血”
freeze thy young blood...
这是命令
It's an order.
把武器给我
Give me the weapon.
“如果你曾经爱过你的父亲”
If thou didst ever thy dear father love.
现在就回医务室去吧
Now get back to the Sickbay.
快
Go on.
很完美的演出
It's going beautifully.
怎么了，出了什么问题？
What is it? What's wrong?
脑海里总有个过去的声音纠缠着我，折磨着我
There was a voice out of the past haunting me, torturing me.
很早以前我曾经出演过另一个人
There was another part I once played long ago.
我从来都没告诉你
I never told you about it.
现在，同样的剧情再次上演
And now that same curtain rises again.
- 时候到了 - 不，父亲
- The time has come. - No, Father.
那一刻永远也不会到来
The time will never come.
今晚，我演出结束过后
Tonight, after my performance,
最后两个能够伤害你的人将会消失
the last two who can harm you will be gone.
- 你在说什么 - 本来有9个人
- What are you saying? - There were nine.
现在只剩两人了
Now there are only two,
他们马上就会消失的，只要我…
and they will be gone as soon as I have--
不要这样看着我
Don't look at me like that.
你做了些什么？
What have you done?
必须得做的事
What had to be done.
他们必须得死
They had to be silenced.
所有的那些人？那七个人？
All of them? All seven?
我双手又沾上了鲜血？
More blood on my hands?
不，父亲，不会再有了
No, Father, not anymore.
我很强大，父亲，没事的
I'm strong, Father. It’s nothing.
第二幕，还有3分钟
Second act, three minutes.
我们马上就好
We'll be ready.
看到了吗？
Don't you see?
所有的鬼魅都死了
All the ghosts are dead.
我亲手将他们葬送的
I've buried them.
你不会再沾上鲜血的
There's no more blood on your hands.
我的孩子，我的孩子啊
My child, my child.
你已让我一无所有
You've left me nothing!
你是唯一一个没有受我当年恶行牵连的人
You were the one thing in my life untouched by what I’d done.
但你现在安全了，父亲
But you're safe now, Father.
我已经拯救了你
I've saved you.
现在，没人能伤害你了
Now no one can touch you.
即使是寇克舰长
Not even Captain Kirk.
说曹操曹操到
See Caesar come.
他敬畏你的伟大
He is awed by your greatness.
你耀眼的光芒
Your shining brightness.
如刀刃般光亮
Bright as a blade
在剑刃染上鲜血之前
before it is stained with blood.
如刀刃般光亮
Bright as a blade.
你们俩都过来
Come with me, both of you.
当然
Of course,
等表演结束
after the play.
演出已经结束了
The play is over.
20年前就该结束了
It's been over for 20 years.
我是名出征的战士
I was a soldier in a cause.
我必须要执行很多残酷的任务
There were things to be done, terrible things.
快停下，父亲，你什么都不必说明
Stop it, Father. You have nothing to justify.
谋杀，逃亡，自杀，癫疯
Murder, flight, suicide, madness.
我从来都不希望你从我的双手沾到鲜血
I never wanted the blood on my hands ever to stain you.
我这么做是为了你，我已经救了你
I did it for you. I've saved you.
通过杀害那七个无辜的人
By killing seven innocent men.
他们不是无辜的，他们是个威胁
They weren't innocent. They were dangerous.
即使是毁灭整个世界我也要拯救他
I would've killed a world to save him.
帷幕已升起，还有一分钟
Curtain going up, one minute.
舰长，他必须要出演
The play, captain, he must go on.
他是伟大的卡里迪安
This is the great Karidian.
- 警卫 - 你不能取消他…
- Guard. - You cannot deny him
最后的演出
his last performance.
蕾诺尔，不
Lenore, don't!
你是逃不出去的
You'll never get off the ship.
这里将成为一个漂浮的坟场
It will become a floating tomb,
在星际间飘荡…
drifting through space...
…伴随着伟大的卡里迪安的灵魂
...with the soul of the great Karidian
在所有到过的星球上演出
giving performances at every star he touches.
我知道该如何使用，舰长
I know how to use this, captain.
- 不 - 暴君
- No. - Caesar,
你的死期到了
beware the Ides of March.
不，孩子，不要！
No, child, don't!
父亲
Father.
自豪的死去吧
O proud Death,
在如此血腥的谋杀之后
what feast is toward in thine eternal cell
尊贵的你，在你无尽的囚牢中
that thou such a prince
享用无尽的盛宴吧
at a shot so bloodily has struck?
帷幕
The curtain.
帷幕升起了
The curtain rises.
它升起了
It rises.
没时间睡觉了
'Tis no time to sleep.
这剧本
The play.
凭着这一本戏
The play's the thing
让我们明白国王的良知
wherein we'll catch the conscience of the king.
医疗记录
Medical report.
她会受到最好的照顾，吉姆，她什么也不记得了
She'll receive the best of care, Jim. She remembers nothing.
她甚至还认为她父亲还活着，还在演出
She even thinks her father's still alive, giving performances
在欢呼的观众面前
before cheering crowds.
你是真的关心她，不是吗？
You really cared for her, didn't you?
准备脱离贝妮莎轨道，舰长
Ready to leave Benecia orbit, captain.
莱斯利先生，请待命
Stand by, Mr. Leslie.
所有频道可用吗，乌乎拉？
All channels cleared, Uhura?
所有频道可用，长官
All channels clear, sir.
- 等你就绪，莱斯利先生 - 正在脱离轨道，长官
- Whenever you're ready, Mr. Leslie. - Leaving orbit, sir.
你是不打算回答我的问题，对吗？
You're not gonna answer my question, are you?
以一级曲速前进，莱斯利先生
Ahead warp factor 1, Mr. Leslie.
那就是你的回答
That's an answer.
本集结束
谢谢观赏